<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>The GoOSe Project</title><link href="http://gooseproject.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://gooseproject.org/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://gooseproject.org/</id><updated>2014-01-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>Proposal: GoOSe Project to join AscendOS</title><link href="http://gooseproject.org/proposal-goose-project-to-join-ascendos.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-01-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Clint Savage (herlo)</name></author><id>tag:gooseproject.org,2014-01-09:proposal-goose-project-to-join-ascendos.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This past Tuesday, January 7, Red Hat and CentOS announced jointly a new CentOS community. This community appears to allow CentOS use Red Hat's resources, to create a new and more expansive community. As you can understand, this may cause some concern, excitement and confusion among the existing EL rebuild communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a rousing meeting today, there is some new movement inside of the GoOSe Project. It appears that due to the changes Red Hat and CentOS announced, it makes sense for there to be a new Special Interest Groups (SIGs) within the newly defined CentOS community. However, there are some external components as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="continuity-sig"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Continuity SIG&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goals of the Continuity SIG would be as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be able to take the SRPMs/SPECs as they were provided from upstream and rebuild without the CentOS infrastructure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Document the process of tooling a rebuild.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide feedback and report bugs to ensure upstream improves packaging, QA, ISO building, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="ascendos-isos"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;AscendOS ISOs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the Continuity SIG described above, it seemed obvious that there is still a desire to keep a separate release. Because CentOS is now a Red Hat community project, it is important that there be a distribution that stands completely on its own, independent of the RHEL/CentOS buils. To accomplish the goals of the Continuity SIG, AscendOS ISOs will be generated for each major and minor release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="mothballing-the-goose-project"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Mothballing The GoOSe Project&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of this effort, the GoOSe Project will retire its workload. Closing down its koji instance and a few other resources. Continuing on will be the github repositories, lookaside cache, documentation and this website. Each service will be evaluated to see which would work best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be links pointing to the AscendOS project as our new base of operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="questions-and-comments"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Questions and Comments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because this is just a proposal, another meeting will be held to better define this proposal and clean up any language, descriptions and goals. An announcement will be made on the GoOSe Project mailing list as well as the AscendOS mailing list. Please drop by #gooseproject or #ascendos on irc.freenode.net if you have input or would like to discuss any of this proposal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;herlo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>GoOSe Linux 6.0 Now Available</title><link href="http://gooseproject.org/goose-linux-60-now-available.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-02-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Clint Savage (herlo)</name></author><id>tag:gooseproject.org,2013-02-27:goose-linux-60-now-available.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The GoOSe Project is pleased to announce the availability of GoOSe Linux 6.0 for i386 and x86_64 Architectures. With this release, the project aims to demonstrate that constructing a build infrastructure and an open community centered around enterprise linux is possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GoOSe-6.0 is based on the upstream's 6.0 Enterprise Release with limited changes where required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="moving-from-el-4-or-el-5"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Moving from EL-4 or EL-5&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since this is the first GoOSe Linux release, it is recommended to reinstall rather than attempting any sort of upgrade process. (Since there aren't prior releases, you'd have to install anyways.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="downloading-goose-linux-6-0"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Downloading GoOSe Linux 6.0&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A direct download is currently available from our mirrors. A list of mirrors are available at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://gooseproject.org/downloads.html"&gt;http://gooseproject.org/downloads.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most mirrors will allow direct DVD downloads over http.  Torrent, FTP and rsync options are in the works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="source-rpms"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Source RPMS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source RPMS are also available on our mirrors. See &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://gooseproject.org/downloads.html"&gt;http://gooseproject.org/downloads.html&lt;/a&gt; for a list of mirrors to download.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="getting-help"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Getting Help&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The GoOSe Project wants to help. The best place to get help is on IRC. Visit #gooseproject on irc.freenode.net to ask any questions or request help. Additionally, there are many other communities who are willing to help. If you think there is an issue with the release, please report it at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/gooseproject/main/issues/new"&gt;https://github.com/gooseproject/main/issues/new&lt;/a&gt;. The GoOSe Project will attempt to resolve all issues, but there are no guarantees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="join-the-goose"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Join the GoOSe&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There have been and will continue to be many challenges to overcome and problems to solve that will be very interesting. Won't you help us? Getting started doesn't require years of training or secret pass phrases. Join our IRC channel (#gooseproject on irc.freenode.net) and the mailing list (&lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:goose-linux&amp;#64;googlegroups.com"&gt;goose-linux&amp;#64;googlegroups.com&lt;/a&gt;) to discuss what GoOSe is and what we do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The GoOSe Project is a meritocracy. Those that do the work and get involved decide its direction and focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with any open source project, GoOSe needs contributors. There is always work to be done. If you have interest in helping the GoOSe Project, check out our &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/gooseproject/main/blob/master/README.rst"&gt;README&lt;/a&gt;. It reveals all the dirt on how to join The GoOSe Project and how to make your first contribution (hint: it's dead simple to get started).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="thanks"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Thanks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who contributed towards making GoOSe 6.0, a list of contributors can be found at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/gooseproject/main/blob/master/CONTRIB.rst"&gt;https://github.com/gooseproject/main/blob/master/CONTRIB.rst&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A special shout out to all who have contributed hardware, network connectivity, hosting and resources for this release. We at the GoOSe Project could not have created the distribution without you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>GoOSe Linux 6.0 Final Test Compose 1 (TC1)</title><link href="http://gooseproject.org/goose-linux-60-final-test-compose-1-tc1.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-02-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Clint Savage (herlo)</name></author><id>tag:gooseproject.org,2013-02-02:goose-linux-60-final-test-compose-1-tc1.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;GoOSe Linux 6.0 Final Test Compose 1 (TC1) is now available for testing. Visit &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://get.gooseproject.org/"&gt;http://get.gooseproject.org/&lt;/a&gt; to obtain the download.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you arrive at the above link, the downloads are under /releases/6.0/Final-TC1/GoOSe/&amp;lt;arch&amp;gt;/.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="testing-this-release"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Testing This Release&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There has been a flurry of work testing releases lately. In doing so, we've created a few new wiki pages to help us test. These pages have been based upon one provided on the Fedora Project Wiki (a big thank you here). The main page is &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/gooseproject/main/wiki/testing-releases"&gt;https://github.com/gooseproject/main/wiki/testing-releases&lt;/a&gt;, which holds links to the different tests which will be performed every release. Currently, there are three pages linked:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/gooseproject/main/wiki/Installation-tests"&gt;https://github.com/gooseproject/main/wiki/Installation-tests&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/gooseproject/main/wiki/base-tests"&gt;https://github.com/gooseproject/main/wiki/base-tests&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/gooseproject/main/wiki/release-criteria"&gt;https://github.com/gooseproject/main/wiki/release-criteria&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each of those pages there are issues so we can make sure to meet our milestones properly. The current milestone is '6.0 Golden GoOSe', linked here: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/gooseproject/main/issues?milestone=3&amp;amp;state=open"&gt;https://github.com/gooseproject/main/issues?milestone=3&amp;amp;state=open&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, as you are going through testing, please update the wiki page &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; the ticket with a status update so we know all the tests have been completed. Thank you all for your hard work, I am really looking forward to a 6.0 Golden GoOSe release this year! :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;herlo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>GoOSe Linux 6.0 Beta Release Candidate 5 (RC5) Now Available!</title><link href="http://gooseproject.org/goose-linux-60-beta-release-candidate-5-rc5-now-available.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-12-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Clint Savage (herlo)</name></author><id>tag:gooseproject.org,2012-12-22:goose-linux-60-beta-release-candidate-5-rc5-now-available.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;GoOSe Linux 6.0 Beta Release Candidate 5 (RC5) is now available for testing. Visit &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://get.gooseproject.org/"&gt;http://get.gooseproject.org/&lt;/a&gt; to obtain the download.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you arrive at the above link, the downloads are under /releases/6.0/Beta-RC5/GoOSe/&amp;lt;arch&amp;gt;/.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The GoOSe Project is always interested in feedback around its project. Please feel free to drop us a line about this release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments/Questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Send us an email &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:goose-linux&amp;#64;googlegroups.com"&gt;goose-linux&amp;#64;googlegroups.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contact us on irc.freenode.net at #gooseproject&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="issues-with-goose-6-0"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Issues with GoOSe 6.0&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you find yourself having trouble installing, using or managing GoOSe Linux, please let us know. The best way is to file issues at our main project site on github, but we’re happy to have the information in any of the ways listed above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Testing can be done by anyone. Please feel free to check our new testing wiki page for information on what tests need to be run and which have already passed. If you have interest in helping us test, thank you, thank you, thank you for the help!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GoOSe Beta-RC5 will be available for 1 week from today. At such time the GoOSe team will decide whether it will be the first Golden GoOSe release. This will be based upon feedback provided, so please do tell us what you think!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;herlo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Get Started with the GoOSe Project</title><link href="http://gooseproject.org/get-started-with-the-goose-project.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-02-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Clint Savage (herlo)</name></author><id>tag:gooseproject.org,2012-02-20:get-started-with-the-goose-project.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The GoOSe Project is a meritocracy. Those that do the work and get involved decide its direction and focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with any open source project, GoOSe needs contributors. There is always work to be done. If you have interest in helping the GoOSe Project, there are just a few steps you need to take to get involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="signup.html"&gt;Sign Up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduce Yourself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take on a Task&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose a Role&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do Work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enjoy the Benefits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting involved in GoOSe is definitely something one should take time to consider. Once involved, it may lead to long hours in front of a computer, talking with cool people and working on cool projects. Don't let that dissuade you, there will also be releases and future events where all members of the GoOSe project will gather and enjoy a weekend of hacking and drinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="learn-about-the-goose-community"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Learn About the GoOSe Community&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The GoOSe Project communicates in many different ways. Here are the most common.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-goose-social-networks"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The GoOSe Social Networks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out our &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/GooseProject"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://identi.ca/group/gooselinux"&gt;Identi.ca&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/gooseproject"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://plus.google.com/114797883199505553142/posts"&gt;Google+&lt;/a&gt;  status updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Planet GoOSe&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://planet.gooseproject.org"&gt;blog posts&lt;/a&gt; by the community. You can add your blog, too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="chat-with-the-goose-community"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Chat with the GoOSe Community&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GoOSe communicates in #gooseproject on &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://irc.freenode.net"&gt;irc.freenode.net&lt;/a&gt;. If you have never used IRC before, check out the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.irchelp.org/irchelp/irctutorial.html"&gt;IRC Tutorial&lt;/a&gt; to get started or use &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://webchat.freenode.net/?channels=gooseproject&amp;amp;uio=MTE9MzY5cf"&gt;web chat&lt;/a&gt; provided by FreeNode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="join-the-discussion"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Join the Discussion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GoOSe has a mailing list, read or sign up below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://groups.google.com/group/goose-linux"&gt;GoOSe Development List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>